<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>


<!-- DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE ... YOU WILL LOSE YOUR WORK -->


<c74object name='jam.dmxusbpro' category='utilities'>

	<digest>Connect to the ENTTEC DMX USB Pro interface</digest>
	<description>Connect to the ENTTEC DMX USB Pro interface. Conrol DMX data with lists. <br/><i>The recommended firmware version is 1.44</i> </description>


	<!--METADATA-->

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name='author'>Jan Mech </metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>utilities</metadata>
	</metadatalist>


	<!--ARGUMENTS-->

	<objarglist>

	</objarglist>


	<!--MESSAGES-->

	<methodlist>

		<method name='blackout'>
			<digest>Set all DMX channels temporarily to 0</digest>
			<description>Set all DMX channels temporarily to 0. </description>
		</method>

		<method name='close'>
			<digest>Close the device connection</digest>
			<description>Close the device connection. If <i>keepsending</i> is 0: Stop sending DMX data. </description>
		</method>

		<method name='devicesettings'>
			<digest>Read firmware version, breaketime, MAB time and refresh rate from the device and send it out the rightmost outlet</digest>
			<description>Read firmware version, breaketime, MAB time and refresh rate from the device and send it out the rightmost outlet. </description>
		</method>

		<method name='open'>
			<digest>Open serial connection to a device</digest>
			<description>Open serial connection to a device. <p>Argument: portname[symbol]</p> </description>
		</method>

		<method name='list'>
			<digest>An even number of integers, indicating pairs of <i>DMX Channel</i> and <i>DMX Value</i>.<br/>Sets the specified channels to the specified values</digest>
			<description>An even number of integers, indicating pairs of <i>DMX Channel</i> and <i>DMX Value</i>.<br/>Sets the specified channels to the specified values. </description>
		</method>

		<method name='deviceserial'>
			<digest>Get the devices serial number</digest>
			<description>Get the devices serial number.<br/><b>NOTE:</b> If the device is currently outputting DMX data, sending this message will set it back to send mode </description>
		</method>

		<method name='menu'>
			<digest>Get list of connected devices and build menu from it</digest>
			<description>Get list of connected devices and build menu from it. </description>
		</method>

		<method name='receive'>
			<digest>Set device to receive DMX messages.<br /><b>Note</b>: Sending a list of DMX values or sending the message deviceserial will set the device into send mode again</digest>
			<description>Set device to receive DMX messages.<br /><b>Note</b>: Sending a list of DMX values or sending the message deviceserial will set the device into send mode again. </description>
		</method>

	</methodlist>


	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->

	<attributelist>

		<attribute name='keepsending' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>If set to 0 (default), the device will stop sending DMX data when the connection is closed</digest>
			<description>If set to 0 (default), the device will stop sending DMX data when the connection is closed. If set to 1 the device will continue to send the last received DMX data after the connection has been closed. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='outmode' get='1' set='1' type='symbol' size='1' >
			<digest>If set to 'onchange' (default) first outlet will only send out DMX data if values have changed</digest>
			<description>If set to 'onchange' (default) first outlet will only send out DMX data if values have changed. <bvr />If set to 'always' every received DMX package will we sent out the first outlet. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='outformat' get='1' set='1' type='symbol' size='1' >
			<digest>DMX data format sent to first outlet</digest>
			<description>DMX data format sent to first outlet. If set to 'list' (default) a list of pairs of <i>DMX Channel</i> and <i>DMX Value</i> will be send out. If set to 'raw' outputs the raw bytes of received DMX data:<br />First byte: Status code. Following Bytes: DMX values.<br /> </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='baudrate' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>Set the baud rate for communicating with the interface</digest>
			<description>Set the baud rate for communicating with the interface. Default: 56700 </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='verbose' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>If set to 0 (default), only serial devices following the ENTTEC USB DMX Pro naming convention will be enabled in a umenu connected to the third outlet</digest>
			<description>If set to 0 (default), only serial devices following the ENTTEC USB DMX Pro naming convention will be enabled in a umenu connected to the third outlet. <br /> If set to 1 all serial devices will be enabled and more information about the coinnection state will be printed to the Max console. </description>
		</attribute>

	</attributelist>


	<!--RELATED-->

	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name='jam.dmxusbpro~' />
		<seealso name='serial' />
	</seealsolist>


</c74object>
